A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - N-P, 2.6
    - Newman, Bernard - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 22 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9672B)
      Interview. Newman was a Republican leader who was appointed to the New York State Supreme Court by Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Nitze, Paul, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9673)
      Interview. Nitze was the financial division director when Nelson Rockefeller was Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs for the Roosevelt administration during World War II. Nitze interview ends at 53 minutes, 1 second. Tape then contains partial interview with Herbert Brownell until end. Brownell was the U.S. Attorney General during the first Eisenhower administration.
    - O'Brien, Jr., Donal, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9675)
      Interview. O'Brien was the Rockefeller family's lawyer for five decades.
    - O'Connor, Frank, and O'Donnell, Jim, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9676)
      Interview. O'Connor was district attorney of Queens, 1955-1965, and the Democratic nominee for governor of New York in 1966. He was president of the New York City Council, 1966-1968, and a Justice of the New York State Supreme Court, 1969-1979. O'Donnell was an aide to O'Connor.
    - O'Neill, Abby, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9677)
      Interview. O'Neill was Nelson Rockefelelr's niece.
    - O'Shaughnessy, William, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9678)
      Interview. O'Shaughnessy was a broadcaster and writer. He was general manager of radio station WVOX in 1965 and bought the station three years later along with WTRN.
    - Ogden, Peter, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9679)
      Interview. Ogden was an architect for the Rockefeller's and IBEC Housing.
    - Oldenburg, Richard, 1982 May 5; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9680)
      Interview. Oldenburg was director of the Museum of Modern Art, 1972-1995.
    - Ortiz, Arthur, 1982 November 9; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9681)
      Interview. Ortiz was an American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) aide.
    - Ottinger, Richard, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9682)
      Interview. Ottinger was a Democrat who served as U.S. Representative for the 24th and later 25th districts of New York from the 1960s to 1980s.
    - Parker, Gen. Theodore, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9683)
      Interview. General Parker (U.S. Army) first served on the staff of Nelson Rockfeller during his tenure in the Eisenhower Administation as Special Assistant to the President for Foreign Affairs. Parker later served as New York State Commissioner of Transporation. Parker interview ends at 134 minutes, 50 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Richard Dunham until end. Dunham was deputy budget director and then director of the budget for Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Dunham was also deputy director of the White House Domestic Council when Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - Parkinson, Elizabeth - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9684)
      Interview. Parkinson was chairman of the Junior Advisory Committee at the Musuem of Modern Art at the invitation of Nelson Rockefeller. She subsequently helpd found the museum's International Council on which she served as president from 1957 to 1966. Parkinson interview ends at 35 minutes, 20 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an unidentified individual regarding investment banking that is unrelated to Reich's Nelson Rockefeller biography.
    - Parkinson, Elizabeth - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9700)
      Interview. Parkinson was chairman of the Junior Advisory Committee at the Musuem of Modern Art at the invitation of Nelson Rockefeller. She subsequently helpd found the museum's International Council on which she served as president from 1957 to 1966.
    - Peabody, Endicott, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9686)
      Interview. Endicott was Governor of Massachusetts, 1963-1965. Interview begins at 3 minutes.
    - Perkins, Roswell B. - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9687)
      Interview. Perkins served on the staff of Nelson Rockefeller while he was Presidnet Eisenhower's Assistant Secretary for U.S. Health, Education, and Welfare Department; First Counsel to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller; Platform planning for 1960 and 1964 Presidential Campaigns.
    - Perkins, Roswell B. - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9688)
      Interview. Perkins served on the staff of Nelson Rockefeller while he was Presidnet Eisenhower's Assistant Secretary for U.S. Health, Education, and Welfare Department; First Counsel to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller; Platform planning for 1960 and 1964 Presidential Campaigns. Perkins interview ends at 312 minutes, 30 seconds. Tape then contains partial interivew with Sheldon Stark until end. Stark was a classmate of Nelson Rockefeller at the Lincoln School and Dartmouth.
    - Perrotta, Fiorvante (Fred), circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9689)
      Interview. Perrotta was assistant counsel to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller; then New York City coordinator of Rockefeller's 1970 gubernatorial campaign. Perrotta interview ends at 127 minutes, 57 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Nelson Rockefeller's brother Laurance Rockefeller until 187 minutes, 16 seconds. Tapen then contains partial interview with Paul Nitze until 237 minutes, 12 seconds. Nitze was director of the financial division of the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs under Nelson Rockefeller. Tape then repeats part of Perrotta interview until 267 minutes, 37 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual regarding investment banking until end. This interview is not connected to Reich's Nelson Rockefeller biography.
    - Percy, Charles, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9690)
      Interview. Percy worked on the Rockefeller Brothers Fund Special Studies Project. He was also a Republican Senator from Illinois, 1967-1985.
    - Phelan, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9691)
      Interview. Phelan was aide to New York State Senate Majority Leader Earl Brydges. Phelan interview ends at 145 minutes, 12 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alton Marshall until end. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller, 1965-1971, and later became president of Rockefeller Center.
    - Plaza, Galo, 1982 October 9; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9692)
      Interview. Plaza was Ecuador's Ambassador to the United States, 1944-1946, President of Ecuador, 1948-1952, and Secretary General of the Organization of American States, 1968-1975.
    - Plumadore, Hayward, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9693)
      Interview. Plumadore was a New York Republican who served as Harrietstown Town Attorney and Supervisor; later was in the State Assembly representing Franklin County, and was county chair for the Republican party.
    - Price, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9694)
      Interview. Price was a campaign aide for Governor Nelson Rockefeller's 1968 presidential campaign. John Price interview ends at 94 minutes, 1 second. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert Price until end. Price managed Nelson Rockefeller's 1964 Republican presidential primary campaign for Oregon.
    - Price, Peter, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9695)
      Interview. Price was a laywer who worked on the Adirondack National Park proposal.
    - Price, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9696)
      Interview. Robert Price managed Nelson Rockefeller's 1964 Republican presidential primary campaign for Oregon. Price interview ends at 79 minutes, 13 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual regarding investment banking. This interview is not connected to Reich's biography on Nelson Rockfeller.
    - Prideaux, Tom, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9697)
      Interview. Prideaux was a classmate of Nelson Rockefeller from the Lincoln School in Manhattan.
    - Purcell, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9698)
      Interview. Purcell was president of the International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC). Purcell interview ends at 71 minutes, 58 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alton Marshall until end. Marshall was Secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and later became president of Rockefeller Center.
  - Q-R, 2.7
    - Reid, Ogden, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9702)
      Interview. Reid was appointed to the New York State Commission on Discrimination in 1961 by Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Reid also served six terms in the United States House of Representatives, 1963-1975. He switched from Republican to Democrat in 1972.
    - Robb, Lillemor (Lee), circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9704)
      Interview. Robb was Chair of New York State Commission on Judicial Conduct and wife of newspaper publisher Gene Robb.
    - Roberts, Al, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9705)
      Interview. Roberts was staff director of the New York State Assembly Ways and Means Committee and member of the Albany Arts Council.
    - Roberts, Laurance, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9706)
      Interview. Roberts was Tod Rockefeller's cousin and a curator (1934-1946) and director (1938-1946) at the Brooklyn Museum. Under his leadership, the Brooklyn Museum produced numerous exhibitions and programs concerning Latin America, with extensive participation in the work of Nelson Rockefeller and the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, under whose auspices the museum produced and circulated traveling exhibitions. Roberts was also involved in the founding of the New York State Council on the Arts in 1960-1961. Roberts interview ends at 30 minutes, 18 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudley until end. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany.
    - Rockefeller, David, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9707)
      Interview. David Rockefeller was Nelson Rockefeller's brother. Rockefeller interview ends at 184 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudley until 220 minutes, 58 seconds. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany. Tape then continues with David Rockefeller interview until end.
    - Rockefeller, Margaretta (Happy) - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9708A)
      Interview. Happy Fitler Rockfeller married Nelson Rockefeller in 1963.
    - Rockefeller, Margaretta (Happy) - Part 2, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9708B)
      Interview. Happy Fitler Rockfeller married Nelson Rockefeller in 1963. Rockefeller interview ends at 118 minutes, 51 seconds.
    - Rockefeller, Margaretta (Happy) - Part 3, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9708C)
    - Rockefeller, Jay, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9709)
      Interview with son of John D. Rockefeller 3rd; nephew of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Rockefeller, Laurance, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9712)
      Interview. Younger brother of Nelson Rockefeller and one of his closest personal advisors.
    - 1. Rockefeller, Nelson on The Phil Donahue Show; 2. Adirondack Bill Signing Ceremony, 1. 1978; 2. 1973 May 22; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9714)
      Tape begins with audio from Nelson Rockefeller's appearance on The Phil Donahue Show (Show number 11187) until 47 minutes, 16 seconds. Tape then contains audio from the Adirondack Bill Signing Ceremony on May 22, 1973 until 67 minutes. Tape is blank for the final six minutes. Rockefeller was Vice President of the United States, 1974-1977, Governor of New York, 1959-1973, Under Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare, 1953-1954, and Assistant Secretary of State for American Republic Affairs, 1944-1945. He also served as trustee, treasurer, and president of the Museum of Modern Art and founded the Rockefeller Brothers Fund in 1940 with his four brothers.
    - Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9711)
      Interview. Nelson Rockefeller, Jr. is the son of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Rockefeller, Rodman, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9715)
      Interview. Rodman Rockefeller was the son of Nelson Rockefeller. He was vice president of the International Basic Economy Corporation, 1968 to 1972, and its chief executive, 1972 to 1980. Rockefeller interivew ends at 25 minutes, 42 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alton Marshall until 47 minutes. Marshall was Governor Nelson Rockefeller's chief aide, 1965-1971, and later became president of Rockefeller Center. Tape then continues with Rodman Rockefeller interview until 278 minutes, 19 seconds. Tape then contains another partial interview with Marshall until end.
    - Rockefeller, Barbara (Bobo) Sears, 1982 November 30; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9470)
      Interview. Bobo Rockefeller was a stage performer who later was the first wife of Winthrop Rockefeller.
    - Rogalin, Wilma, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9716)
      Interview. Rogalin was vice chair of the New York State Republican Committee and president of its Women's Federation.
    - Romney, George, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9718)
      Interview. The governor of Michigan in the 1960s, Romney ran unsuccessfully for the Republican presidential nomination in 1968. He later served as U.S. Secretary of Housing and Urban Development in the Nixon administration.
    - Ronan, William, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9719)
      Interview. Ronan was a long-time aide and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller and a senior advisor to the Rockefeller family. He designed and served as the first chairman of the New York City Metropolitan Transportation Authority, 1968-1974. He then served as chairman of the Port Authority of New Yokr and New Jersey, 1974-1977.
    - Rosenbaum, Richard, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9720)
      Interview. Rosenbaum was Monroe County (NY) Republican chair, 1968 to 1970; New York State Supreme Court justice, 1970 to 1972; and New York Republican State Committee chair from 1973 to 1977.
    - Rosenberg, Anna, 1983 September 22; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9721)
      Interview. Rosenberg was a friend and public relations advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. She served in President Franklin Delano Roosevelt's administration and advocated for Rockefeller to Roosevelt, leading to his appointment as Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs.
    - Rosenberg, Tom, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9722)
      Interview. Rosenberger was Anna Rosenberg's son. Rosenbeg interivew ends at 54 minutes, 20 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with John Byron until end. Byron was director of construction of the South Mall for the State Office of General Services, an agency Governor Nelson Rockefeller created to oversee the project.
    - Rothberg, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9723)
      Interview. Tape contains two separate interviews with individuals about investment banking and are not connected to Reich's Nelson Rockefeller biography.
    - Ruebhausen, Oscar, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9724)
      Interview. Ruebhausen was a lawyer who served as a personal advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. Under Governor Rockefeller, Ruebhausen served in a number of capacities, including as chair of the Special Task Force on Protection from Radioactive Fallout, as Special Adviser on Atomic Energy, and as chair of a panel on insurance holding companies. He also served as one of Governor Rockefeller's executors.
    - Ruggieri, Bernard, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9725)
      Interview. Ruggieri was chair of the New York City Democratic Party in the early 1970s. Also served as a lawyer representing the legislative and executive branches of New York State and New York City.
    - Rumsfeld, Donald - Interview 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9726A)
      Interview. Rumsfeld was White House Chief of Staff and later Secretary of Defense during President Gerald Ford's administration. Rumsfeld interview ends at 77 minutes, 39 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with J. Lawrence Murray until end. Murray worked for New York politician Frank Moore in various capacities during the 1950s and 1960s and served as acting chief administrative officer of the State University of New York, 1963-1964.
    - Rumsfeld, Donald - Interview 2, 1982 April 13; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9726B)
      Interview. Rumsfeld was White House Chief of Staff and later Secretary of Defense during President Gerald Ford's administration.
    - Rusher, Bill - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9727A)
      Interview. Rusher was publisher of National Review magazine who helped found the Conservative Party of New York in 1961 and the American Conservative Union in 1964. He worked on Senator Barry Goldwater's successful 1964 campaign for the Republican presidential nomination.
    - Rusher, Bill - Part 2, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9727B)
    - Ryan, Jr., Andrew, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9728)
      Interview. Ryan was Member of the New York State Assembly from the Capitol area in the 1960s through 1980s. He was known for opposing the creation of the Adirondack Park Agency by the state legislature.
  - S-T, 2.8
    - Scelsi, Michael, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9730)
      Interview. Scelsi was executive director of the New York State Republican Committee, 1959-1965. Then after serving as Appointments Officer for two years, Governor Nelson Rockefeller appointed Scelsi to the New York State Civil Service Commission. Scelsi interview ends at 148 minutes, 2 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Schuler, Raymond - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9732)
      Interview. Schuler was instrumental in establishing the New York Department of Transportation and was appointed transportation commissioner in 1972 by Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Schuler was also the founder of The Business Council, New York's largest lobbying organization.
    - Schuler, Raymond - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9733)
    - Schwenk, Edwin, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9734)
      Interview. Schwenk was Republican Party chair of Suffolk County, New York, from 1967 to 1977.
    - Scribner, Fred, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9735)
      Interview. Scribner was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller. He served in the administration of President Dwight D. Eisenhower as UnderSecretary of the Treasury, and he later served as general counsel to the Republican National Committee. Scribner interivew ends at 70 minutes, 5 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with General Theodore Parker until end. Parker was a general in the United States Army and served on Nelson Rockefeller's staff when Rockefeller was Special Assistant to the President for Psychological Warfare. Parker also served as New York State Commissioner of Transportation.
    - Sears, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9736)
      Interview. Sears was a Republican pollitical strategist and served as advisor to Richard Nixon during the 1968 presidential campaign. He then served as Deputy Counsel to President Nixon, 1969-1970, and managed Ronald Reagan's 1976 presidential campaign.
    - Seidman, William, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9737)
      Interview. Seidman was executive director of Presdient Gerald Ford's Economic Policy Board and served as the president's assistant for economic affairs until 1977. Seidman interview ends at 46 minutes, 51 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alan Miller until end. Miller was New York State Commissioner of Mental Hygiene, 1966-1975.
    - Shafer, Raymond, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9731)
      Interview. Shafer was Governor of Pennsylvania, 1967-1971, and gave the nominating speech for Governor Nelson Rockefeller at the 1968 Republican National Convention.
    - Shapiro, George, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9738)
      Interview. Shapiro was counsel to New York Governor Thomas Dewey.
    - Sharkey, Bill - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9739A)
      Interview. Sharkey was chief of revenue estimating for the New York State Department of Taxation and Finance prior to Nelson Rockefeller's administration. He then worked on Governor Rockefeller's staff starting in 1959, where he focused on tax and budgeting projects.
    - Sharkey, Bill - Part 2, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9739B)
      Interview. Sharkey was chief of revenue estimating for the New York State Department of Taxation and Finance. He moved on to work in the governor's office in 1959 where he worked on various tax and budgeting projects under Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Sharkey interview ends at 155 minutes, 4 seconds. Tape then contains a partial phone call with an unidentified individual until 159 minutes, 30 second. Tape then contains partial interview with Tanya Melich unitl end. Melich was an aide to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Shaw, Elizabeth, 22 November 1982; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9740)
      Interview. Shaw was public relations director at the Museum of Modern Art.
    - Slater, Ilene, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9741)
      Interview. Slater was an executive assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Slote, Leslie, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9742)
      Interview. Slote was press secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1966-1968. Slote interview ends at 32 minutes, 51 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with F. Clifton White until 47 minutes, 1 second. White was a political consultant and campaign manager for Republican Party and New York Conservative Party candidates. He was also a leader of the Draft Goldwater Committee, 1961-1964. Tapen then continues with Slote interview until end.
    - Spad, Carl, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9743)
      Interview. Spad was New York State Appointments Officer; State Chair of Young Republicans.
    - Spencer, Stuart, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9744)
      Interview. Spencer was a political aide for Nelson Rockefeller during the 1964 Republican presidential primaries.
    - St. Thomas, William - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9745)
      Interview. St. Thomas was Republican party chair of Saratoga County, New York.
    - St. Thomas, William - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9746)
    - Stafford, Ronald, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9747)
      Interview. Stafford was a New York State senator from 1966 to 2002, for the district that includes a significant portion of Adirondack State Park. He was instrumental in bringing the internatioanl winter Olympics to Lake Placid in 1980.
    - Stark, Sheldon, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9748)